iesabroad.org 2019-09-01

# Privacy Policy | IES Abroad | Study Abroad

IES Abroad and SAF are committed to respecting and protecting your privacy and helping you make the most of your time on the Internet within a trusted environment. This Privacy Policy applies to IES Abroad’s and SAF’s website and governs its data collection, usage, and services.

**Information We Collect**

Any information collected on this site is used only to facilitate a more personal experience for the user. We do not sell or distribute any information about its users to outside organizations. This privacy policy discloses how we collect, protect, and use information gathered about you on our website. Your use of this website signifies your acceptance of this policy. We hope that this disclosure will help increase your confidence in our website and enhance your experience on our site.

You can use our website without divulging any personally identifiable information including your email address. Our website does not collect identifiable information about individuals except when such individuals specifically provide such information on a voluntary basis, such as when registering at our website, requesting a catalog, or completing our online application. We use such information collected to improve and customize the content you see, to provide the products, services or membership benefits you request, and to contact you with related information.

We collect and temporarily store certain information about your visit for use in site management and for security purposes only. We collect and analyze this information because it helps us to better design our website to suit your needs. We may also automatically collect information about the web content you view in the event of a known security or virus threat. This information includes:

  1. The Internet domain from which you access our website (for example, “xcompany.com” if you use a private Internet access account, or “yourschool.edu” if you connect from an educational domain);
  2. The Internet Protocol (IP) address (a unique number for each computer connected to the Internet) from which you access our website;
  3. The type of browser (e.g., Firefox, Internet Explorer, Chrome) used to access our site;
  4. The operating system (e.g., Windows, Mac OS, Unix) used to access our site;
  5. The date and time you access our site;
  6. The Universal Resource Locators (URLs), or addresses, of the pages you visit;
  7. Your username, if it was used to log in to the website; and
  8. If you visited this website from another website, the URL of the forwarding site.

**Use of Cookies**

A cookie is a small file transmitted from the website to your computer to allow it to remember specific session information. Our website uses "cookies" to enable you to utilize our online application (e.g. in order for the NEXT and SUBMIT buttons to function properly). Cookies are uniquely assigned to you and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. We NEVER share or sell information contained within cookies with any other person or third party. Any information that is obtained through a cookie is information a user has voluntarily submitted through the site.  There are two types of cookies:

  * **Session** :  Session cookies only last as long as a user’s web browser is open and is deleted once the browser is closed.
  * **Persistent** :  Persistent cookies are saved on your hard drive and help to determine whether users are new or returning visitors.

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies, if you prefer. However, if you choose to decline cookies, you will not be able to fully utilize the interactive features of our website.

**Links to Other Web Sites**

Our website utilizes links to other websites. We hold no responsibility for the content, privacy practices, or other site links to those websites. The inclusion of any link to such a site does not create or imply any approval or endorsement by us of that site or of products or services referenced there. IES Abroad makes no representations or warranties of any kind or nature as to any other website that you may access through this one. These links are included on our website for reference purposes only.

**Choice/Opt-out**

We provide you the opportunity to ‘opt-out’ of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information.

If you no longer wish to receive communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included on our website or you may contact us at 1.312.944.1740 or by mail at 33 W. Monroe St., Suite 2300, Chicago IL, 60603 to opt-out.

**Emails**

By requesting a catalog from our site, you authorize IES Abroad and/or SAF to contact you via email in the future regarding its study abroad internship or other programs. You are able to unsubscribe from our email distribution list by writing to [info@IESabroad.org](mailto:info@IESabroad.org)  and asking to be removed from our mailing list. Please put "REMOVE" in the subject area and in the body copy include your full name and email address. We do not distribute email addresses under any circumstance.

**Security**

All IES Abroad information technology systems and infrastructures meet or exceed industry standards of security, encryption, and controls.

**Links from Other Web Sites**

IES Abroad is not responsible for the content of any other site linked to this one. The inclusion of any link to our site on another site's pages does not create or imply any approval or endorsement of that site by IES Abroad or SAF.

**Children's Privacy**

We recognize the privacy interests of children and we encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children’s online activities and interests. This Site is not intended for children under the age of 13. IES Abroad and SAF not target their services or this Site to children under 13. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13.

**Disclaimer**

IES Abroad and SAF may disclose personal information if required by law.

**Updates to the Privacy Policy**

We will occasionally amend this privacy policy, as needed, and therefore encourage you to periodically review this policy.  We are committed to maintaining a secure and current website.

**Contact IES Abroad**

If you have any questions about this privacy statement or the privacy practices of this website, please contact us at [info@IESabroad.org](mailto:info@IESabroad.org), attn: Director, Web Applications.
